# Rohit Sahu

### Web Developer

Web Developer with 2+ years of experience in designing and developing user interfaces, testing, debugging. I've extensive experience using multiple standard programming languages. Proven ability in optimizing web functionalities that improve data retrival and workflow effeciencies.



- 🔀 rohitsahu728@gmail.com
- Guwahati, India
- in linkedin.com/in/rohit-sahu-62043615a
- S rohit52594@outlook.com
- github.com/rohit52594
- medium.com/@rohitsahu728

- 8402081401
- rohit52594.github.io
- **y** @rohit8402
  - facebook.com/rernr
- stackoverflow.com/users/12099177/rohit-sahu
- instagram.com/rohits\_1997

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Web Developer OTECHNIX

04/2019 - Present

Guwahati, Assam

Working as a Web Developer with React, Node.js, PHP. Growing here with learning and using tools like AWS, Firebase, Postman, Workbench. Codeigniter, Laravel, React using Hooks, Node.js etc.

### On Job Trainee

DiTech Process Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

11/2018 - 03/2019

Guwahati

Done Internship here as On Job Trainee. Learned working with XHTML, CSS3 for making EPUB's and working with XML files etc

## **CERTIFICATES**

Web Developer (07/2015 - 06/2016)

Junior Web Developer from NSQF Level 5

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

Nazira College

06/2015 - 12/2018

Nazira, Sivasagar

#### Courses

 C, C++, Java, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, Database management, Software structure and development, Web Development etc.

# **Microsoft Certified Systems Expert**

Guwahati

09/2018 - 02/2019

Guwahati

Courses

 MCSE (Microsoft Certified Systems Expert) Windows Server. Active Directory Installation, DHCP, IP Addressing, LAN Configuration, Group Policy Object & OU.

## **SKILLS**

ReactJS Amazon Web Services PHP NodeJS

Bootstrap SCSS MaterialUI Linux jQuery

Firebase RDS Version Control using Git Jira

AOP/OOP SSH

## **PROJECTS**

#### buysara.com (codeigniter)

E-commerce site with multiple user roles: admin, deliverer, vendor, franchise, employee and customer.

### onor.world (reactjs)

Used ReactJS Hooks and admin panel in Core UI. (under development)

#### friendstambola.com (reactis)

Tambola game frontend developed in ReactJS and backend in PHP

## patidarrangcollege.com (codeigniter)

Admission portal

#### homserv.in

House & Home service providing developed in codeigniter with 2 PWA (Client and Partner)

#### Моге...

and other authenticated admin panels, CMS, MLM and inventory management projects

## **LANGUAGES**

Hindi

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

#### Assamese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

# INTERESTS

Listening to Music

Coding

Travelling

Video Games

Blogging

Cooking